Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ffarah (LinkedIn) farahfarouk.github.io/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Business Analytics
Forecasting
Cash Flow Forecasting

Languages

French (Native or Bilingual) Korean (Full Professional) Spanish (Limited Working)

Intro to SQL for Data Science

Certifications

Advanced Deep Learning with Keras in Python
Introduction to Python
Building Chatbots in Python
Python Data Science Toolbox (Part 1)

Honors-Awards

The National Society of Collegiate Scholars Award

Farah Farouk, MSIS

Data Scientist

Orange County, California Area

Summary

Analytical and process-oriented data scientist with +3 years in data analytics and data engineering, and with extensive knowledge of computational statistics, big data, and machine learning. Seeking to use my expertise in data science applications to deliver insightful and action-oriented solutions to solve real-world problems and to exceed company targets.

```
✓# SKILLS

## Advanced Time Series Analysis

## ETL

## Deep Learning and Neural Networks

## Data Engineering and Warehousing

## Machine Learning

## Data Blending and Visualization

## Data Property Pro
```

✓# PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES:

Python (Pandas, NumPy, matplotlib, seaborn, TensorFlow, Keras, psycopg2, scikit-learn, PySpark, spaCy, pipenv, Pypeline)
R
SQL
JAVA

√# SOFTWARE:

HTML ## CSS

Alteryx
Power BI
Tableau
AWS (Redshift, SageMaker, Athena, ML)
Snowflake
SAP
Apache Hadoop, Spark.

√# SPOKEN AND WRITTEN LANGUAGES: French (native), Arabic, Korean.

Updated resume and certifications attached below ##

Experience

Edwards Lifesciences Senior Data Scientist November 2019 - Present (5 months) Irvine, CA

✓# Leading a team of three analysts to provide analytics support to the Critical Care business unit for post-market surveillance, and collaborating proactively with various business and technical units to identify business opportunities and to design innovative data solutions.

✓# Implementing advanced machine learning models, data mining methods, statistical analysis and RPA using Python, to automate quality engineering processes.

√# Integrating multiple data sources (SQL Server, MySQL and Oracle databases, REST APIs, JSON, text/CSV, etc.) and processed non-structured data types within dynamic dashboards using Power BI, Power Apps, and Power Automate to lead and improve data-driven decision-making.

Data Driven Investor
Technical Writer and Consultant
May 2019 - Present (11 months)
Greater Los Angeles Area

√# Writing periodical articles on the rise of artificial intelligence and creating
user tutorials for Alteryx and Python programs.

√# Designing Python courses, including a course on the use of time series analysis to predict stock performance.

Upwork
Data Scientist
March 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month)
Greater Los Angeles Area

√# Designing and maintaining ETL processes and data pipelines using
Python's psycopg2, PySpark, SQLContext, AWS S3 and Redshift.

✓# Conducting sentiment analyses and designing predictive models using Python's TensorFlow and Keras libraries. California State University, Fullerton

1 year

Graduate Research Assistant

March 2019 - August 2019 (6 months)

Fullerton, CA

√# Collecting primary and secondary data as appropriate to the specific objectives of the study.

√# Pre-processing data and providing ready access to all experimental data for the faculty researcher.

✓# Developing research protocols using deterministic and probabilistic models, and machine learning.

Website Administrator

January 2019 - June 2019 (6 months)

Fullerton, CA

√# Updating Upward Bound's website with new content.

✓# Updating and creating pages, applying different styles and layouts using CSS and HTML.

Pre-College Advisor and Tutor September 2018 - June 2019 (10 months)

Fullerton, CA

✓# Serving high school students with academic advisement, college exposure and mentoring through workshops and Saturday Success Academies through the Upward Bound program at the Anaheim Union High School District and the Fullerton Joint Union High School District.

√# Tutoring students in mathematics, statistics, and French to improve their
academic success.

√# Hosting and supporting community events, workshops and college visits to endorse the importance of higher education.

CSUF Sales Leadership Center Sales Consultant/Competitor August 2018 - August 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Fullerton, CA

Actively participated in sales consulting events, and extensively used business and marketing analytics to drive sales forecasts.

Competed in:

√# So You Think You Can Sell Competition in Fall 2018 hosted by Stanley Black & Decker

√# The Titan Sales in Spring 2019 hosted by Henry Schein and So Cal Office
Technologies

√# The Sales Games in Spring 2019 hosted by American Capital Group

The Stimulus Effect Tutor 2016 - 2017 (1 year) Irvine, CA

√#Tutoring students in French and providing academic support.

SG HOLDING GROUP LTD (SG SAGAWA USA)

Operations Supervisor 2016 - 2016 (less than a year) Gardena, CA

√# Operated 6 freight consolidations per week to Japan from California to cut shipping costs and to reduce transit time.

✓# Automated and managed the reporting environment for all air and ocean
imports and exports to East Asia through the company's logistics software
CargoWise and the transportation management system, to capitalize on supply
chain opportunities through visibility and control.

✓# Created detailed transit reports and KPI dashboards on Excel for upper management.

Kintetsu World Express (U.S.A.), Inc. Ocean Export Analyst 2015 - 2016 (1 year) Rancho Dominguez, CA

√# Received, reviewed, and processed all export documentation (Ocean Bills
of Lading, Insurance Certificates, Certificates of Origin, etc.) for an assigned
base of accounts, including KWE's top account Shin-Etsu Handotai Group
(SEH).

✓# Automated booking of cargo space on vessels through carriers and coloaders, and coordinated with 3PL companies to ensure a smooth cargo delivery to the Port of Los Angeles and the Port of Long Beach.

✓# Provided prompt customer service by informing clients of the status of their shipments, and by issuing detailed statistical ocean transit reports to improve customer experience, to help clients better understand export logistics processes, and to also identify any irregularities or delays in shipments.

√# Issued detailed statistical transit reports and dynamic dashboards using Excel and Tableau.

Education

California State University, Fullerton

Master of Science - MS, Information Systems and Decision Sciences, Concentration in Business Analytics · (2018 - 2019)

University of California, Los Angeles
Postbaccalaureate Degree, Computer Systems & Applications
Programming · (2016 - 2018)

American University

Bachelor of Arts - BA, International Relations, Thematic Spec. in International Trade, minor in Computer Science · (2010 - 2015)